<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
          "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [

    <!ENTITY dhtitle "User Manuals">
    <!ENTITY dhcommand "glite-wms-job-info">
    <!ENTITY dhsection "1">
    
    <!ENTITY dhfirstname "Alvise">
    <!ENTITY dhsurname "Dorigo">
    <!ENTITY dhemail "alvise.dorigo@pd.infn.it">
    <!ENTITY dhcontrib "Developer of the WMS User Interface">
    
]>



<refentry>

    <refentryinfo>
        <title>&dhtitle;</title>
        <productname>&dhcommand;</productname>
        <authorgroup>
            <author>
                <firstname>&dhfirstname;</firstname>
                <surname>&dhsurname;</surname>
                <contrib>&dhcontrib;</contrib>
                <address>
                    <email>&dhemail;</email>
                </address>
            </author>
        </authorgroup>
    </refentryinfo>

    <refmeta>
        <refentrytitle>&dhcommand;</refentrytitle>
        <manvolnum>&dhsection;</manvolnum>
    </refmeta>

    <refnamediv>
        <refname>&dhcommand;</refname>
        <refpurpose>Allows retrieving information about submitted jobs.</refpurpose>
    </refnamediv>

    <refsynopsisdiv>
        <cmdsynopsis>
            <command>&dhcommand;</command>
            <arg choice="opt"><option>options</option></arg>
            <arg choice="req"><replaceable><![CDATA[<operation options>]]></replaceable></arg>
            <arg choice="req"><replaceable><![CDATA[<job ID>]]></replaceable></arg>
        </cmdsynopsis>
    </refsynopsisdiv>

    <refsect1>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para><command>&dhcommand;</command> allows retrieving useful information about the user delegated proxy, the delegated identification details of
        the user, the jdl of a previously submitted job, etc. Each piece of information has to be queried through the proper option. E.g.:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para><command>glite-wms-job-info --delegationid myDelegationID</command></para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><command>glite-wms-job-info --jdl mySubmittedJobID</command></para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><command>glite-wms-job-info --proxy mySubmittedJobID</command></para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>

        <para>This  command is only available for glite version >= 3.1.</para>
    </refsect1>

    <refsect1>
        <title>OPTIONS</title>
        <variablelist>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--config <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<configfile>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-c <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<configfile>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>if the command is launched with this option, the configuration file pointed by configfile is used.
                    This option is meaningless when used together with <option>--vo</option> option</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--debug</option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>when this option is specified, debugging information is displayed on the standard output and written also either into 
                    the default log file: <filename>&dhcommand;<![CDATA[_<uid>_<pid>_<time>.log]]></filename> 
                    located under the <filename>/var/tmp</filename> directory or in the log file specified with <option>--logfile</option> option.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--delegationid <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<idstring>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-d <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<idstring>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>if this option is specified, the user proxy associated to the id delegated previously will be displayed.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--endpoint <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<serviceURL>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-e <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<serviceURL>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>when  this  option is specified, the operations are performed contacting the WMProxy service represented by the given serviceURL.
                    If it is not used, the endpoint contacted is that one specified by the <envar>GLITE_WMS_WMPROXY_ENDPOINT</envar> environment variable.
                    If none of these options is specified and the  environment  variable  is  not set, the service request will be sent to one of the endpoints
                    listed in the WMProxyEndPoints attribute in the user configuration file (randomly chosen among the URLs of the attribute list).
                    If the chosen service is not available, a succession of attempts are performed on the other specified services until the connection with one 
                    of these endpoints can be established or all services have been contacted without success. In this latter case the operation can not be 
                    obviously performed and the execution of the command is stopped with an error message.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--help</option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Displays command usage.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--input <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<filepath>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-i <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<filepath>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Allow the user to select the desired job among the ones contained in the file located in filepath.
                    This option cannot be used if the jobId has been specified. 
                    A job has to be selected specifying the numbers associated to the job identifier</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--jdl <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<jobid>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Retrieves and displays the jdl registered to the LB service for the specified JobId: 
                    the WMProxy service where the job was submitted is contacted and asked for needed information.
                    This option is only available from glite version >= 3.1.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--jdl-original <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<jobid>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-j <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<jobid>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Retrieves and displays the original jdl submitted by the user to the WMProxy service.
                    This information might be quite different from the registered jdl, mostly for parametric and collection of jobs.
                    This option is only available from glite version >= 3.1.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--logfile <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<filepath>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>When this option is specified, a command log file (whose pathname is filepath) is created.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--noint</option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>if this option is specified, every interactive question to the user is skipped and the operation is continued (when possible)</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--output <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<filepath>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-o <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<filepath>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Stores the retrieved information into the specified file instead of the standard output.
                    The specified file path can be either a simple name or an absolute path (on  the submitting machine).
                    In the former case the file filepath is created in the current working directory.
                    This option is only available from glite version >= 3.1.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--proxy <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<JobID>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <term><option>-p <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<JobID>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Retrieves and displays information for the proxy delegated with the specified JobId: 
                    the WMProxy service where the job was submitted is contacted and asked for needed information.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--version</option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>displays WMProxy client and servers version numbers.
                    If the <option>--endpoint</option> option is specified only this service is contacted to retrieve its version.
                    If it is not  used, the endpoint contacted is that one specified with <envar>GLITE_WMS_WMPROXY_ENDPOINT</envar> environment variable.
                    If the option is not specified and the environment variable is not set, all servers listed in the WMProxyEndPoints attribute of the user configuration file are contacted.
                    For each of these service, the returned result will be displayed on the standard output (the version numbers in case of success; otherwise the error message).</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry>
                <term><option>--vo <replaceable class="parameter"><![CDATA[<voname>]]></replaceable></option></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>this option allows the user to specify the Virtual Organisation she/he is currently working for.
                    If the user proxy contains VOMS  extensions then  the VO specified through this option is overridden by thedefault VO contained in the proxy
                    (i.e. this option is only useful when working with non-VOMS proxies).</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

        </variablelist>
    </refsect1>

    <refsect1>
        <title>EXAMPLES</title>
        
        <para>Display information for the proxy delegated to the WMProxy service with the specified identifier:</para>
        <para><command>glite-wms-job-info -d delegationid</command></para>
        
        <para>Display information for the proxy delegated with a previously submitted Job:</para>
        <para><command>glite-wms-job-info -p JobId</command></para>
        
        <para>Display the submission string registered to LB server for a previosly submitted Job:</para>
        <para><command>glite-wms-job-info --jdl JobId -o OutputFile</command></para>

        <para>Display the original submission string sent to the WMProxy service for a previosly submitted Job:</para>
        <para><command>glite-wms-job-info -j JobId</command></para>
        
        <para>Send the request to the WMProxy service whose URL is specified with the <option>-e</option> option:</para>
        <para><command>glite-wms-job-info -d delegationid -e https://wmproxy.glite.it:7443/glite_wms_wmproxy_server</command></para>

        <para>Store  into  a  file the submission string registered to LB server for a previosly submitted Job:</para>
        <para><command>glite-wms-job-info --jdl JobId -o OutputFile</command></para>

        <para>When <option>--endpoint</option> is not specified, the search of an available WMProxy service is performed according to 
        the modality reported in the description of the -<option>--endpoint</option> option.</para>

    </refsect1>

    <refsect1>
        <title>FILES</title>
        <para><filename>voName/glite_wms.conf</filename>: The user configuration file. 
        The standard path location is <filename>$GLITE_WMS_LOCATION/etc</filename> (or <filename>$GLITE_LOCATION/etc</filename>);</para>
        
        <para><filename><![CDATA[/tmp/x509up_u<uid>]]></filename>: A valid X509 user proxy;
        use the <envar>X509_USER_PROXY</envar> environment variable to override the default location</para>
        
        <para>JDL: The file containing the description of the job in the JDL language located in the path specified by jdl_file (the last argument of this command); 
        multiple jdl files can be used with the <option>--collection</option> option.</para>

    </refsect1>
    
    <refsect1>
        <title>ENVIRONMENT</title>
        <para><envar>GLITE_WMS_CLIENT_CONFIG</envar>: This variable may be set to specify the path location of the configuration file.</para>
        <para><envar>GLITE_WMS_LOCATION</envar>: This variable must be set when the Glite WMS installation is not located in the default paths (<filename>/usr</filename>).</para>
        <para><envar>GLITE_LOCATION</envar>: This variable must be set when the Glite installation is not located in the default paths (<filename>/usr</filename>).</para>
        <para><envar>GLITE_WMS_WMPROXY_ENDPOINT</envar>: This variable may be set to specify the endpoint URL</para>
        <para><envar>GLOBUS_LOCATION</envar>: This variable must be set when the Globus installation is not located in the default path (<filename>/usr</filename>).</para>
        <para><envar>GLOBUS_TCP_PORT_RANGE</envar>="<![CDATA[<val min>]]> <![CDATA[<val max>]]>": This variable must be set to define a range of ports to be used
        for inbound connections in the interactivity context</para>
        <para><envar>X509_CERT_DIR</envar>: This variable may be set to override the default location of the trusted certificates directory,
        which is normally <filename>/etc/grid-security/certificates</filename>.</para>
        <para><envar>X509_USER_PROXY</envar>: This variable may be set to override the default location of the user proxy credentials,
        which is normally <filename><![CDATA[/tmp/x509up_u<uid>]]></filename>.</para>
        <para><envar>GLITE_SD_PLUGIN</envar>: If Service Discovery querying is needed, this variable can be used in order to set a specific (or more) plugin, 
        normally bdii.</para>
        <para><envar>LCG_GFAL_INFOSYS</envar>: If Service Discovery querying is needed, this variable can be used in order to set a specific Server
        where to perform the queries: for instance LCG_GFAL_INFOSYS="gridit-bdii-01.cnaf.infn.it:2170"</para>
    </refsect1>

</refentry>

